fredperry.com 2018-12-21

# Privacy | Fred Perry UK

Last Modified: April 2018

Fred Perry Limited and its affiliates (collectively, “Fred Perry”, or “we”) are committed to safeguarding and respecting your privacy.

INTRODUCTION

**What is this policy about?**

This policy (together with our [terms of use](https://www.fredperry.com/aboutus/terms) and any other documents referred to on it) describes the types of personal information we collect on this website when you sign up to our newsletter, purchase a product or take part in a competition, how we may use that information and with whom we may share it. The notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of your personal information (regardless of where you visit our website from). We also tell you how you can reach us to ask us to (i) access, change or not use the personal information you have provided to us, (ii) withdraw any consent you previously provided to us, (iii) tell us to stop communicating with you about our products, and (iv) answer any questions you may have about our privacy practices.

This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

**Why should I read it?**

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

By visiting https://www.fredperry.com/ you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy

**Who is responsible for this policy?**

The Fred Perry Group is made up of different legal entities. This privacy notice is issued on behalf of the Fred Perry Group so when we mention, "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice, we are referring to the relevant company in the Fred Perry Group responsible for processing your data. Fred Perry Limited of 37 Mount Pleasant, Clerkenwell, London, WC1X 0AA, England, is the controller responsible for this website.

We have appointed a data protection officer (DPO) who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, please contact the DPO as specified in the “How Do You Contact Us” section below.

This privacy notice is provided in a layered format. Click on one of the links below to jump to the listed section:

  1. How Do We Collect And Use Your Information?
    * Shopping
    * My Account
    * Surveys, Competitions and Giveaways
    * Electronic Newsletters and Other Marketing Communications
    * Blogs
    * Email to a Friend
    * Contact Us
    * Cookies, Web Beacons and other Information We Collect by Automated Means
    * Customer Assistance
    * Statistics
    * Third Party Sources
    * Other Purposes
    * Change of Purpose
  2. How Do We Share Your Information?
  3. Do We Transfer Your Personal Information to Other Countries?
  4. How Do We Protect Your Personal Information?
  5. How Long Do We Keep Your Personal Information?
  6. How Can You Access, Amend or Correct The Information We Hold On You?
  7. What Happens If I Choose Not To Provide My Personal Information?
  8. Do We Link to Other Sites?
  9. How Do We Update Our Privacy Policy?
  10. How Do You Contact Us?

## 1\. How Do We Collect And Use Your Information?

**1.1** Individuals may choose to provide personal data (such as name, contact details and payment information) through this website and through our customer service line. Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

**1.2** We do not collect any special categories of personal data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

**1.3** Here are the ways you may provide the information and the types of information you may submit. We also tell you how we may use the information

**Shopping**

**1.4** You may be able to purchase Fred Perry products and gift cards on this website. To process your purchase, we ask for information such as your first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, marital status, title, date of birth, gender, billing and delivery/shipping address, telephone number, email address, bank account and payment card information. We use this information to process your purchase, confirm your order and deliver the items to you. If you provide us with your prior consent and/or if otherwise permitted under applicable law, we also may use your contact information to communicate with you about our products, services and promotions.

**1.5** If you purchase an item on this site or ask us to deliver your purchase to someone else, we ask for the recipient’s name, postal address and email address. We use this information to send the item to the recipient. Before you disclose to us the personal information of another person, you must obtain that person's consent to both the disclosure and the processing of that personal information in accordance with the terms of this policy.

**My Account**

**1.6** You may be able to register to create an account on this website. To do so, we ask for information such as your name, email address, password, purchases and orders made by you. You also may provide your age and gender.

**1.7** Through the “my account” feature, you can store billing and shipping information so you won’t have to enter it again when you make another purchase on this site. You also can store payment card information and details of your past purchases from us. In addition, you can save your credit card information on your account for faster checkout. To use this feature, we ask you to provide your credit card information and the corresponding billing address.

**1.8** You can create and save an address book on your account. You can delete entries in the address book at any time. We will not use or disclose the information you delete from your address book..

**Surveys, Competitions and Giveaways**

**1.9** On this website, you may be able to participate in surveys, competitions, giveaways and other promotions. If you choose to participate in these promotions, we may ask you for information such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses. We use the information you provide to administer our competitions, giveaways and other promotions. We also may use the information to communicate with you about our products, services and promotions, but only if you have given us your consent to do so.

**Electronic Newsletters and Other Marketing Communications**

**1.10** You may be able to sign up on this site to receive electronic newsletters and promotional emails from Fred Perry, including new ideas, special offers and event information. To sign up, we may ask you for information such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, age, gender, your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties, your shopping preferences and your communication preferences. We use this information to send you communications about our products and services, invitations to specials sales and events at stores located near you, and notices of new arrivals. We also use this information to tailor our newsletters to reflect your preferences.

**1.11** You can choose at any time not to receive marketing emails from us by clicking on the unsubscribe link within our marketing emails. You also may use the email preferences section of the “my account” feature to opt out of receiving marketing emails or to specify which, if any, communications you would like to receive from us. There is no charge to you to unsubscribe.

**Blogs**

**1.12** You may be able to submit comments to blogs we host on this website. You may include personal information in your comment, and you also may submit your name with your comment. We use your name to identify you as a commenter.

**Email to a Friend**

**1.13** You may be able to share certain content from this website with your friends. To send information to your friends, we may ask for your friends’ and your email addresses. We use this information only to fulfil your request. We do not retain the information you provide in connection with this feature, except to send the requested content. We will not include any other advertisements within the messages sent to your friends.

**Contact Us**

**1.14** If you communicate with us through the “Contact Us” link on this site, we may ask you for information such as your name, email address, and telephone number. We use this information to respond to and communicate with you about your questions and comments.

**Cookies, Web Beacons and other Information We Collect by Automated Means**

**1.15** We obtain certain information by automated means when you visit our website, such as the internet protocol (IP) address of the device you use to connect to the Internet, the pages accessed, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, other technology on the devices you use to access this website and information about how you use our website and products. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our website to our visitors and understand what products and services you might prefer. We collect this information through various means, such as “cookies” and “web beacons.”

  1. Cookies  
Like many companies, we use “cookies” on this website. Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer’s hard drive when you visit certain websites. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site. We use cookies, for example, to preserve the contents of your virtual shopping bag between visits. We also use cookies to measure activity on the site and determine which areas and features of the site are the most popular. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.fredperry.com/aboutus/cookies-policy).
  2. Web Beacons  
Certain pages on this website contain "web beacons" (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). Web beacons are often used in combination with cookies. We use them for internal purposes, such as to obtain the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, and the type of browser used to view the page. We also retain service providers who use web beacons to assess the effectiveness of our email communications and learn what pages our visitors viewed. Unlike cookies, you cannot decline web beacons. However, setting your browser to decline cookies or to prompt you for a response will keep web beacons from tracking your activity.
  3. Performance Tools  
We may use performance tools such as [Google Analytics](https://www.google.co.uk/analytics) to measure the effectiveness of our advertising and determine how visitors use this website. Google Analytics tools, including cookies and web beacons, allow us to collect information such as the state/country of residence and zip code/postcode from which our visitors come and the IP addresses of our visitors' computers. You can opt out of aggregation and analysis of data collected by companies like Google Analytics.

**1.16** To find out more about the way we use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies, and how to manage your settings and preferences, please visit our [Cookie Policy](https://www.fredperry.com/aboutus/cookies-policy).

**Customer Assistance**

**1.17** You may call our customer service line for information about our products or personal shopping advice. If you do so, we may ask you for information such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number and, if you choose to make a purchase, your payment card information. We use this information to respond to your request and process your transaction.

**Statistics**

**1.18** We also collect, use and share aggregated data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your usage data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect aggregated data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

**Third Party Sources**

**1.19** In addition to the ways we collect information about you described above, we also may obtain information about you from third parties (for example, our sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, Sage Pay, PayPal and Klarna). We will share information with such service providers only to the extent necessary for them to provide their relevant service (in this instance, processing payments made via our website, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds).

**1.20** We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

**Other Purposes**

**1.21** We may also use your personal information to provide you with products or services you request (such as tailoring services or processing returns), enhance your shopping experience and communicate with you about our products, services and promotions.

**1.22** In addition, we may use your personal information for internal purposes, such as fraud and theft prevention, accident reporting, development and administration of our sites and stores, data analytics, and compliance with our legal obligations, policies and procedures.

**Change of Purposes**

**1.23** We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us as specified in the “How Do You Contact Us” section below.

**1.24** If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

**1.25** Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

**2.1** We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal information about our customers, except as described here.

**2.2** We may share the personal information with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries.

**2.3** We may share your information with selected third parties including:

  1. Business partners, licensees, suppliers, service providers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you. Third parties are only authorised by us to use or disclose the information we provide them, to the extent necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements.
  2. Advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about you.
  3. Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site.
  4. Third party fraud screening agents for the purpose of assessing your credit score where this is a condition of us entering into a contract with you.

**2.4** We may also disclose information about you, if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our [terms of use](https://www.fredperry.com/aboutus/terms#tandcu), our [terms and conditions of supply](https://www.fredperry.com/aboutus/terms#tandcs), and/or any of our other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Fred Perry, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**2.5** In addition, we reserve the right to transfer personal information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided to us in a manner that is consistent with this policy. Following such a sale or transfer, you may contact the entity to which we transferred your personal information with any inquiries concerning the processing of that information.

## 3\. Do We Transfer Your Personal Information to Other Countries?

**3.1** The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

## 4\. How Do We Protect Your Personal Information?

**4.1** We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. For example, all information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers and any payment transactions will be encrypted. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. We have also put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

**4.2** Unfortunately, however the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

**4.3** Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

**4.4** Children under the age of eighteen may not shop on this website without the consent of their legal representatives.

## 5\. How Long Do We Keep Your Personal Information?

**5.1** We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

**5.2** To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

**5.3** In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data. In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

## 6\. How Can You Access, Amend or Correct The Information We Hold On You?

**6.1** It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

**6.2** You have a number of rights in relation to your information under data protection laws. The right to:

  * Request access to your personal data.
  * Request correction of your personal data.
  * Request erasure of your personal data.
  * Object to processing of your personal data.
  * Request restriction of processing your personal data.
  * Request transfer of your personal data.
  * Right to withdraw consent.

**6.3** If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, you may contact us as specified in the “How Do You Contact Us” section below. Please include in your request, your name, email address, postal address, a copy of a utility bill showing your current address or other proof of address, and a copy of your identity card or passport certified by a solicitor or bank. This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**6.4** You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances. Subject to applicable law, we may limit or deny you access to personal information where providing such access is unreasonably burdensome or expensive under the circumstances.

**6.5** We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

**6.6** You may also choose not to receive marketing communications from us by clicking on the unsubscribe link in our marketing emails or contacting us as specified in the “How Do You Contact Us” section below. Please include your name, email address and postal address if you send us your request by email or postal mail.

## 7\. What Happens If I Choose Not To Provide My Personal Information?

**7.1** Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

## 8\. Do We Link To Other Site?

**8.1** This website may, from time to time, contain links, plug ins and applications to and from third party websites, for your convenience and information. These sites may be operated by companies not affiliated with Fred Perry. Linked sites may have their own privacy policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any of these linked websites. We have no control over, and are not responsible for the content of any websites that are not affiliated with Fred Perry, any use of those websites, or the privacy practices of such third-party websites.

## 9\. How Do We Update Our Privacy Policy?

**9.1** This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices or relevant laws. Where appropriate, we will post a prominent notice on the site to notify you of any significant changes to our policy and indicate at the top of the notice when it was updated.

**9.2** Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

**9.3** The data protection law in the UK will change on 25 May 2018. Although this privacy notice sets out most of your rights under the new laws, we may not yet be able to respond to some of your requests (for example, a request for the transfer of your personal data) until May 2018 as we are still working towards getting our systems ready for some of these changes.

**10.1** If you have any questions or comments about this policy, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us as indicated below:

  1. Contact form: [here](https://www.fredperry.com/contacts)
  2. Telephone: UK Freephone number 0808 129 3515
  3. Email: [ecommerce@fredperry.com](mailto:ecommerce@fredperry.com)
  4. Address: 37 Mount Pleasant, Clerkenwell, London, WC1X 0AA, England

**10.2** You also have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.
